

INFO



Phone (720) 453-8137

E-mail



javier.augusto@gmx.net



LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/javieraugusto

STRENGHTS

- Executive Trusted Advisor
- Capability Development
- Technical Delivery Management
- Security Service Design
- Team Building

SKILLS

- SOC Consulting
- MSSP Business Development
- Security Process Improvement
- Security Engineering
- Incident Management
- CMM Program Management

QUALIFICATIONS

- Certified Information Security Manager (CISM)
- Bachelor of Science –
 Computer Systems
 Information University of Blumenau







JAVIER O AUGUSTO

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE



Fueled by passion, Javier Augusto posses an extensive expertise of sixteen (16) years of Cybersecurity Operations Center experience acquired in diverse Fortune 1000 customers, dedicated to building, maturing and operating SOCs from a vendor angle.

Mr. Augusto currently serves as an R&D Principal Engineer and Technical Success Manager for On-Prem & Cloud UEBA (XDR beta) solutions, evangelizing Next-Gen SOC's vision to the world, providing direct customer interaction, supporting the partner ecosystem, and a constant improvement of security offerings.

Previously, Mr. Augusto acted as Global Managing Principal for Micro Focus (former HP ArcSight) Security Intelligence Operations Consulting team, providing consulting expertise in Managed Security Services and Operations, Capability and Maturity Program Management, Security Engineering and Threat Hunting Services to a worldwide customer base.

Additionally, Mr. Augusto provided subject matter expertise architecture solutions for two Gartner Magic Quadrant SIEM leaders (ArcSight and QRadar) to global customers.

Mr. Augusto has successfully:

- Acted as Professional Services Delivery Manager for global ArcSight SIEM/UEBA projects
- Delivered SOC build projects in the Americas, APJ & Middle East
- Delivered MSSP Assessments & Business Development Projects Worldwide
- Global SOC Architect Big Four
- Global MSS Solution Architect & Technical Leader Global MSSP

Proven projects with the following customers:



















Company



















EXPERIENCE

Q 2019 - Current Principal Security Engineer, ArcSight Intelligence UEBA/XDR Research and Development Technical Success Manager, ArcSight Intelligence UEBA On-Prem/Cloud Lead Solution Architect for SIEM and UEBA solutions (Layered Security Analytics) OpenText Cybersecurity (formerly known as Interset - a Micro Focus start-up acquisition)

- Managing and delivering end-to-end ArcSight UEBA security analytics on-prem deployments (Kubernetes+Vertica data lake) and Azure Cloud projects (Azure AKS Private Clusters).
- Responsible for a client engineering support team, overseeing all aspects of customer integrations.
- Scoped, created, and delivered custom solutions, presentations and demonstrations of Next-Gen SOC solutions, presenting to C-Level Executives and non-technical audience.
- Performed Security Data Lake acquisition pipeline Health Checks to ensure proper tooling vs. business alignment and requirements were met.
- Worked with upper management to define strategic operational goals based on customer's executive-level feedback and delivery strategies, ensuring Security / Business strategy alignment.
- Co-author of immersive hands-on workshops for customers and partners.
- Identified potential On-Prem/Cloud/SaaS opportunities based on technical requirements and synergies from similar customer experiences. Participated in Territory/Account planning meetings.

O 2017 - 2019

Global Principal Consultant - Worldwide Cyber Strategic Solutions & SIOC Micro Focus (formerly known as HPE Security / ArcSight Professional Services)

Global Principal dedicated to building, maturing and operating Security Operations Centers (SOCs), Hunt and Incident Response (IR) solutions and capabilities of the world's largest enterprises.

- Built and managed worldwide SOCs and IR solutions and capabilities.
- Performed strategic consulting engagements and advisory services for Security Operations, Hunt Teams, and Incident Response programs.
- Led Managed Security Service Provider (MSSP) engagements, interfacing with new and existing ArcSight MSSP customers, assisting with strategic business development service catalogs.
- Led SOC maturity assessments, workshops (HP Protect and in-house) and large-scale projects across different verticals.
- Provided management, expert guidance and oversight to SIOC Consultants across the world.

O 2015 - 2017

Global Managing Principal - Security Intelligence & Operations Consulting Hewlett Packard Enterprise Security (formerly known as HP ArcSight Professional Services)

- Practice Manager. Provided team leadership for an industry leading security intelligence professional services team that builds, matures and staffs Security Operations Centers.
- Delivery Manager for ArcSight and Atalla Professional Service engagements throughout Latin America.
- Managed SOC engagement delivery, tracked project deliverables, managed project risk, performed quality assurance on deliverables, managed resource utilization, tracked project financials.
- Supported sales efforts by briefing key customer representatives, present Practice services, deliver workshops, develop customer proposals where needed, and ensure buy-in of proposed solutions from top management levels at the customer.
- Performed role of counselor and coach, provided leadership and support for delivery teams, staff and subcontractors, developed and mentored consultant career paths, and actively participated in staff recruitment and retention activities.

EXPERIENCE

2014 - 2015

Global Security Architect, Security Operations & Optimization Consulting IBM Security

- Global Senior resource for IBM Security Services Global Center of Competence (CoC), leading Security Operations consulting projects, assisting with SOC optimization and maturity assessments for a large pool of worldwide customers.
- Performed SOC Foundation design activities providing end-to-end visibility of IT security attacks and integration of customers' Incident Response programs in a SIEM-content to incident management capability, going from operations to corporate response, creating a uniform security monitoring and response capability program.
- Lead delivery consultant for Security Operations consulting projects, assisting with optimization and maturity of customers' IBM QRadar SIEM posture, ensuring security requirements were met.

2012 - 2014

Senior Security Architect, MSS / QRadar Solutions IBM Security

- Senior Enterprise Security Architect for LATAM market, focused on Oil & Gas, Finance and Telecommunications markets.
- Technical Lead for IBM QRadar SIEM solutions: design, implementation and consultancy. Data Leak Prevention, and Malware Protection Systems (FireEye, Trusteer).
- Lead Solutions Architect for Managed Security Services, Managed Web Protection Services (Akamai) as well as Security Intelligence services (IBM X-Force).
- Provided security architecture and design leadership assistance to sales teams across different IBM pillars.
- Designed and delivered IBM Brazil's biggest distributed QRadar deployment at a top-tier Brazilian
 Financial customer.

O 2008 - 2012

Security Escalation Engineer, Managed Security Services Security Analyst, Managed Security Services

IBM Security (formerly known as Internet Security Systems - ISSX)

- Technical leader and Senior resource for IBM MSS Global Customers, a global market leader in Managed Security Services.
- Provided network security architecture design, integration, troubleshooting and deployment assistance for Intrusion Detection and Prevention solutions (Proventia), multi-vendor highavailability Firewall/UTM solutions, Security Event and Information Management solutions (ArcSight), as well as managed VPN solutions.
- Managed and delivered technical guidance for top-revenue Managed Security Services accounts.

REFERENCES

Ralph Bernard, Director
Trustwave Government Solutions
Denver, Colorado
970-397-6420

Rob Sandoval, VP Trustwave Security Services Denver, Colorado 303-941-7398 Travis Turney, Sr Product Manager SimScope Greater Miami, Florida 857-333-9242